Wow. That ripped.
와우!
찢어졌네?
시원하게 찢어졌어
That ripped real nice!
비켜서 들어오라고 했잖아
알아? 비켜서 미끄러지듯이
How many times do I have to tell you?
You turn and slide.
Turn and slide.
You don't turn and slide.
비켜서 미끄러지듯?
당장 갖다 버려!
You throw it out!
때깔 곱게 빼 입을 때마다
파상풍 주사를 맞아야겠어?
I get tetanus shots
every time I get dressed!
We're not throwing it out.
I built it with my own hands!
버리다니, 내 손으로
직접 만든 건데
그럼 팔면 어떨까?
How about we sell it?
All right.
좋아
하지만 얘들부터 설득해
But you'll have to tell them.
Can we stick you in another cabinet?
They seem all right with it!
다른 캐비닛은 어때?
괜찮다는데?
The One with the Cat
Hey, why did the chicken
fall out of the tree?
병아리가 왜
나무에서 떨어졌게?
Why?
왜?
Because you have
doody on your head.
올라가면 더 이상하잖아
벤이 얘기하면 웃긴데
Yeah, it was funnier
when Ben told it.
Hey, Monica.
It's Chip.
- 모니카? 나 칩이야
- 옳다구나!
칩이 누군데?
Who's Chip?
오늘 만나서 반가웠어
내 전화번호야
It was good running
into you today.
555-9323
전화해, 끊을게
My number is 555-9323.
Give me a call.
칩 매튜스야
"Chip" is Chip Matthews.
The guy who took Rachel to the prom?
Why's he calling you?
레이첼하고 졸업무도회에
갔던 친구?
왜 너한테 전화를 했지?
오늘 은행에서 만났는데
여전히 끝내주더라
Because I ran into him at the bank.
He is still so cute.
학교 최고의 인기남인데
너 억세게 운 좋다!
You're so lucky! He's like
the most popular guy in school!
누가 아니래!
I know!
칩? 모니카야
Chip? Hi, it's Monica.
그래
좋아
그럼
좋지, 안녕
Oh, my God!
We just had the best conversation!
너무나 환상적인 대화였어
I was just leaving.
나갈 거야
잘됐네
Good.
I've got a report to read.
리포트 읽어야 되니까
8장인데 잠들면 어떡하나?
It's eight pages.
I hope I don't fall asleep.
Why? Did you write it?
왜? 직접 쓰셨나?
와우, 이것 봐라
칩 매튜스가 전화했네
Look at that!
Chip Matthews called.
I wonder what he wants.
속셈이 뭘까?
실은...
Well, actually....
내가 다른 남자랑 잘 준비가
끝났다는 걸 눈치 챘나 보지?
I bet he sensed that I was ready
to have sex with another guy.
뭐 어때...
전화해 봐
Why don't you give him a call?
좋아
- 들어도 괜찮겠어?
- 물론이지
-Are you sure you want to hear this?
-I'm sure.
칩, 나 레이첼이야
레이첼 그린
Chip!
Hi, it's Rachel.
Rachel Greene.
메시지 남겼어?
You left me a message?
룸메이트가 적어놨던데
Yes, you did.
My roommate wrote it down.
모니카 겔러?
Monica Geller?
정답입니다
Oh, that's right!
모니카한테 전화한 거래요
He called to ask out Monica.
얼굴 좀 팔리겠다 얘
That's got to be embarrassing.
곤드레만드레!
떡이 된 계집!
Dumb drunken bitch
Thank you!
감사합니다
Here's a question.
질문 하나
미시시피 동부에서 제일가는
오크제품은 어디서 구할까요?
Where'd you get the "finest oak
east of the Mississippi"?
미국에서 가장 예쁜
신발 끈은 어디서 구했지?
First tell us where you got
the prettiest lace in the land.
It's your ad.
- 너희가 낸 광고야
- 괜찮지?
Looks good?
"Stunning entertainment center, fine
기막힌 장식장...
이태리 장인의 손길
Fine ltalian craftsmanship."
장식장 팔려고 내놨어?
You're selling
the entertainment center?
Why? I love it.
왜, 난 좋던데
-You want it?
-No.
- 갖고 싶어?
- 전혀
Gepetto?
제페토 영감님?
Five thousand dollars?
5천 달러?
제정신입니까?
Are you insane?
The ad alone cost $300.
광고비만 3백 달러야
I'm changing it
to $50 or your best offer.
잔말 말고 50달러로 바꿔
'부르는 게 값'이든지
남는 게 없잖아
그러고도 회계사냐?
What kind of profit is that?
And you call yourself an accountant?
아니
아냐?
What do you do?
무슨 일을 하시죠?
I can't believe you don't know.
내 직업도 모른단 말이야?
- 난 모르는데
- 나도...
I actually don't know.
Oh, my God, no!
Shoo, kitty!
안돼, 저리 가, 훠이!
안된다니까, 건터? 내 기타
케이스에 고양이가 있어요
There's a kitty
in my guitar case.
쉬잇! 다들 사달래잖아
Everyone's gonna want one.
자, 이리 온
Come on, you!
이 녀석
Crazy!
-Oh, my God!
-What?
맙소사
왜?
아무 것도 아냐
Nothing.
뭐가 잘못됐어?
What's wrong?
그냥...
강한 느낌이 뇌리를 때려
이 고양이는 우리 엄마야
I just have this really strong feeling
that this cat is my mother.
The mom you met in Montauk?
She was a cat?
몬토크에 사는 분이
고양이였어?
That makes the fact that she owns
beach-front property all the more impressive.
왠지 재산이 좀 많다 싶었어
No. She was a human lady.
아니, 그 분은 인간이고
This is the spirit of my mom, Lilly.
The one that killed herself.
이 고양이는 자살하신
우리 엄마의 영혼이야
Have you been taking your grandmother's
glaucoma medicine again?
너 또 혹시 할머니의
녹내장 약 먹은 거니?
No, Dr. Skeptismo.
아니옵니다, 박사님
I'm sure.
First of all, there's the feeling.
이건 확실해
먼저 느낌이 오니까
또 내 기타 케이스로 갔잖아
안감이 오렌지색 펠트야
And for another,
she went into my guitar case...
...which is lined with orange felt.
My mother's favorite fish
was orange roughy.
오렌지색 금붕어를
제일 좋아하셨어
Cats like fish.
고양이는 생선을 좋아해
You had me with orange felt.
오렌지색 펠트가 감동이다
Hi, Mommy!
안녕, 엄마?
17년 만에 이런 미소는
처음이야
I haven't seen
this smile in 17 years.
-Phoebe's mom's got a huge pair of
-Let it go!
- 피비 엄마한테 커다란...
- 잊어버려
나 왔어
When were you going to tell me
that you're dating Chip?
칩 매튜스 만난다는
얘기는 언제 할래?
Now?
지금
Can I go out with him?
만나도 괜찮겠지?
괜찮긴 뭐가 괜찮아
그 자식이 어떤 짓을 했는데
No. I can't believe you'd want to
after what he did to me.
That thing at the prom?
졸업무도회에서?
I couldn't find him for hours!
He was having sex with Amy Welsh!
에이미 웰쉬랑 놀아나느라
두 시간이나 실종됐던 작자야
That was in high school.
How can it still bother you?
고등학교 때 얘기야
다 지난 일이라고
맞다, 젖소부인 모니카
Oh, yeah, you're right, Moni-cow.
Okay, I hear you.
다 들린다
Why do you have
to go out with Chip?
세상에 남자가 칩밖에 없나?
우린 다른 학교에 다녔잖아
We went to different schools.
아니, 같은 학교에 다녔어
We went to the same school.
You went to one where you were popular.
넌 학교에서 인기 좋았잖아
You rode on Chip's motorcycle
and wore his letterman jacket.
칩의 재킷을 걸치고
걔 오토바이를 타고 다녔지
난 특수 제작된
밴드 유니폼을 입었어
I went to one where I wore a band
uniform that was specially made.
They had that specially made?
특수 제작된 거였어?
It was a Home Ec project.
가정학 실습과제였지
Oh, my God! They said
it was for the mascot.
저런, 마스코트한테
입힌다고 하더니
Back then I thought that I'd never
get to go out with a Chip Matthews.
그땐 칩 매튜스랑
사귈 꿈도 못 꿨어
Now he's called me up
and asked me out.
이제 날 만나자고 하잖아
The fat girl inside me really
wants to go. I owe her this.
예전의 뚱보였던 여자애가
불쌍하다는 생각도 안 들어?
I never let her eat.
이건 굶주림의 보상이야
가서 만나라
-You go out with him.
-Really?
- 정말?
- 그럼
섹스는 다른 남자랑
하는 게 어떨까?
If possible, could you leave him
and have sex with another guy?
I'll try.
노력해볼게
Any luck getting rid of
the entertainment center?
장식장 건은 어떻게 됐어?
There were a couple calls,
but they won't work out.
전화는 몇 번 왔는데
잘 안 될 것 같아
Joey has a very careful
screening process.
선별작업이 아주 까다로워
Not everyone is qualified
to own wood and nails.
아무나 나무궤짝을
차지할 순 없지
그만해
Stop it!
자꾸 빠져나가려고 하네
꼭 살아 계실 때처럼
She keeps trying to get away.
Just like when she was alive.
How long is your mom
going to be with us?
너희 어머닌 여기
얼마나 더 계실 거니
I'm not sure.
글쎄, 새엄마가 계신다는
사실을 인정해야겠지
I guess until she gets used to
the fact that there's...
...a new mom.
자기를 버릴까봐 두려운 거야
Now she's worried
that she'll be replaced.
That's not going to happen, is it?
절대 그런 일은 없지?
- 들어가서 전화할게
- 여기서 하지 왜
I have to go make a call.
Why not use this phone?
해변에 계신 엄마한테
전화 드리는 거야
I'm returning a call from
a certain mom at the B-E-A-C-H.
I just spelled the wrong word.
거기가 아닐 수도 있고
어쨌든 꼬리 달린
사람 앞에선 못해
Anyway, I don't want to do it
in front of someone with a tail.
그런 말 안 한다고 했잖아
Hey, you swore you
would never tell.
So am I crazy, or does Phoebe's mom
remind anyone else of a cat?
너희들도 피비 엄마가
고양이를 닮은 것 같니?
Ross, don't start.
그만둬
왜, 저 고양이 안에
여자가 들어있다고?
You actually believe
there's a woman inside that cat?
I believe it.
난 믿어
- 아닐 거야
- 믿는다니까
No, you don't.
Yes, I do.
No, you
아니...
You know what?
이거 알아?
You won't suck me into this.
난 말려들지 않아
말려들걸?
넌 항상 옳으니까
Sure I will.
Because you always have to be right.
내가 언제...
그래, 좋아
I do not always have
Okay, okay.
'주라기 공원'도
불가능한 건 아니지
Jurassic Park could happen.
And you know what? Actually,
I do think Kirk was smarter than Spock.
'스타트렉'에서도 스파크보단
커크가 영리하잖아
You were kidding about the
Kirk-Spock-thing, though, right?
커크랑 스파크
얘긴 농담이지?
와우! 꽤 쓸만하네
That's pretty nice.
꽤 쓸만해?
"Pretty nice"?
Pardon my roommate.
He wanted to marry this.
결혼할 사이였으니
선생이 이해하시오
50달러는 없는데
맞바꾸는 게 어때요
We don't have $50.
But would you trade for it?
We got a canoe.
우리 카누랑
I don't think we need a canoe.
- 카누를 어디다 쓰게
- 받는 게 좋을 거요
You got to take it.
좋소, 그냥 가져가시고
집에 가서 카누를 버리쇼
Just take the entertainment center.
Then when you get home,
throw the canoe away.
버리다니
내가 만든 건데
We're not throwing it away.
I built it.
Good for you!
그래야지!
You won't believe
what I found on a telephone pole.
얘들아, 전봇대에
이게 붙어있지 뭐야
많이 본 거지?
Look familiar?
Apparently Phoebe's mother
also goes by the name "Julio."
피비 엄마의 또 다른
이름은 훌리오였군
Wait a minute. This is not the
same cat. This cat's only this big.
잠깐, 이 고양이는
거기가 요만하잖아?
소녀가 고양이를 찾고 있어
무슨 뜻인지 알아?
A little girl's looking for this cat.
Know what that means?
현상금 2백 달러를
5로 나누면?
Yeah! $200 reward split five ways!
Do we have to tell her?
- 말해야 할까?
- 당연하지
-Yes, we do.
-But it's made her so happy.
저렇게 좋아하는데
Little girl misses her cat.
고양이를 찾는 소녀와
Crazy lady thinks
her mother is in a cat.
고양이 안에서 엄마를 찾는
정신 나간 여자
I have to go have
dinner with my son.
아들하고 저녁 먹기로 했어
피비 만나면 꼭 얘기해?
Can I trust that when you see Phoebe,
you will tell her?
그래...
Thank you.
고맙다
늘 입바른 소리야
I hate when Ross is right.
He is right, isn't he?
- 맞는 말이잖아
- 이번에는 틀렸는지도 모르지
This might be one time
when he's wrong.
-You think?
-Oh, no. He's right.
- 그럴까?
- 아니, 맞아
- 나 왔어
- 그래
- 피비, 너희 어머니 말이야
About your mom.
How's that going?
잘 돼가?
너무 좋아
So great.
We took a nap together today.
오늘 같이 낮잠을 잤는데
내 배 위에서 가르랑거렸어
Mom fell asleep
on my tummy and purred.
That's so sweet.
저런
I'm gonna get some coffee.
커피 좀 가져올게
고마워
What'd you say, Joe?
I'll be right there.
뭐라고, 조이?
금방 갈게
- 피비...
- 이건 정말이지...
I just feel so....
나도 간다!
-All right!
-I'm coming already!
Not yet, not yet, not yet!
아직 아냐!
-Hello, Chip.
-How you doing?
- 안녕, 칩?
- 잘 지냈어?
나야 좋지, 블루밍데일의
멋진 직장, 근사한 친구들
I'm great!
Got a great job.
I have wonderful friends.
Though I'm not seeing anyone now,
I've never felt better about myself.
만나는 사람은 없어도
기분은 그만이야
So, Monica ready yet?
모니카는 준비됐나?
금방 나올 거야
에이미 웰쉬는 어때?
She'll be out in a second.
So, Chip, how's Amy Welsh?
에이미 웰쉬?
그 애를 본 게...
Amy Welsh?
I haven't seen her since
So, Monica about ready?
모니카는 준비됐나?
왔어?
- 너 정말 예쁘다
- 왜 이래
-Wow, you look great.
-Thanks.
-Well, you guys have fun.
-Catch you later.
- 재미 많이 봐라
- 그래
- 또 보자
- 안녕, 칩
Bye, Chip.
-Are you sure you're okay about this?
-Actually
정말 괜찮은 거지?
- 실은...
- 다행이다!
Okay, great.
This is the unit for you.
선생을 위한 가구입니다
Sturdy construction,
tons of storage.
튼튼한 구조, 넉넉한 수납공간
성인남자도 들어갈 수 있죠
Some big enough to fit a grown man.
-What?
-Yeah, I got in there myself once.
뭐요?
네, 제가 들어가 봤어요
My roommate bet me $5 I couldn't.
친구 놈은 안 된다고
5달러를 걸더군요
Then he stuck a board
through the handles and locked me in.
손잡이에 빗장을 끼워서
갇히고 말았지만
It was funny till I felt
like it was a coffin.
관 속에 들어간 기분이
들기 전까진 재미있었죠
No, you can't fit in there.
It's not deep enough.
그럴 리가...
깊이가 안 되는데
Oh, yeah?
그래요?
If I can't...
안되면... 까짓 거
5달러 깎아드리죠
...I'll knock $5 off the price.
All right, you have
yourself a deal.
- 그렇게 합시다
- 좋아요
See?
I told you.
어때요, 내 말이 맞죠?
Sometimes I come in here
just to get away from it.
가끔 여기서 명상도 한답니다
Hey, a nickel!
이보쇼, 5달러
Here we are.
여기야
You still have the Chipper!
아직 '치퍼'를 갖고 있네?
The what?
뭐?
That's what we called
your motorcycle in high school.
고등학교 때 네 오토바이를
그렇게 불렀어
A motorcycle's a chopper.
오토바이는 '차퍼'
넌 '칩'
And you're Chip.
Never mind.
잊어버려
그거 재미있다
I think it's cute.
와우, 치퍼는 헤퍼
A lipper from Chipper.
Are you still in touch with anyone?
연락하는 동창 있어?
레이첼하고...
There's Rachel...
...and that's it.
How about you?
그게 다야
너는?
I still hang with Simens and Zana.
I see Spindler, Levine, Kelly.
시먼스하고 재나랑
아직 어울려 다니고
스핀들러, 러빈, 켈리는
자주 만나지
I run into Goldie...
골디, 스틱, 브라운, 설코프
맥과이어는 가끔 봐
...Stick, Brown, Sulkov, McGuire...
...J.T., Beardsley.
제이티랑 비어슬리도
Is that all?
- 그게 다야?
- 졸업하면 연락이 끊기잖아
After high school,
you kind of lose touch.
I ran into Richard Dorfman.
리처드 도프몬도 만났구나
걔는 어때?
-How is he?
-Me and Simens gave him a wedgie.
안 좋을 걸? 나랑 시몬스가
속옷을 당겨줬으니까
Isn't he an architect?
- 건축가라고 했던가?
- 건축가도 속옷은 입거든
They still wear underwear.
Oh, my God!
어럽쇼?!
What?
뭐야!
Are you all right?
너 괜찮냐?
그래
What happened?
이게 뭔 사태야?
Oh, man, he promised
he wouldn't take the chairs!
의자는 놔둔다더니
How were you locked in?
Where the hell is all of our stuff?
그 안에서 뭐해
우리 세간 다 어쨌어!
This guy came by
to look at the unit...
장식장 보러 온 인간이
어른은 못 들어간다잖아
...and he said
it won't fit a grown man.
So you got in voluntarily?
제 발로 들어갔어?
쉬운 장사가 어디 있나?
I was trying to make a sale!
If I ever run into him,
you know what I'll do?
놈을 다시 만나면
내가 뭘 할 줄 알아?
Bend over?
뒤로 공중제비?
And then Zana just let one rip!
재나가 거기서
방귀를 뀌는 거야!
Not that I don't enjoy
talking about high school...
애들 험담하는 건
나도 꽤 즐기는 편이지만
...because I do.
Maybe we can talk
about something else.
다른 얘기는 어때?
넌 어디서 일하는데?
I don't know where you work.
-You know where I work.
-I do?
알면서 왜 물어?
알다니?
우리 영화관에
많이 왔었잖아
The movie theater.
You used to come in all the time.
Still at the Multiplex?
- 그 멀티플렉스 말이야?
- 놓치기 아까운 직장이지
Like I'd give up that job!
Free popcorn and candy
anytime I want?
공짜 사탕에 팝콘이 넘쳐나고
I can get you posters.
포스터 좀 갖다 줄까?
Thanks, I'm set.
됐네요
Oh, you know who came
in the other night? Peters.
전에 누가 온지 알아?
피터스야
Told me he just went out with
Leslie Maskin. Got to third base.
레슬리랑 갈 때까지
간 모양이야
Do you still live
with your parents?
- 아직 부모님이랑 사니?
- 늦게 들어가도 돼
Yeah, but I can stay out
as late as I want.
You know, with all of our stuff gone,
the unit doesn't seem that big.
세간이 없어지니까
장식장도 아담한데?
Why couldn't he have been a kidnapper.
납치범이면 좋았을 걸
They really got you guys.
Your TV, the chairs.
몽땅 털어갔네
TV에다 의자까지
Your microwave, the stereo.
전자렌지, 오디오
Man, he took the five of spades!
스페이드 5도 없어!
No, here it is.
아니, 여기 있다
Oh, my God! What happened?
이게 무슨 일이야?
조이의 탄생 28년 후
내 집에 강도가 들었어!
Joey was born, and then
28 years later, I was robbed!
So how was your date?
데이트 어땠어?
Well, I always wanted to go out
with Chip in high school.
고등학교 때 난 언제나
칩과 사귀고 싶어했지?
Tonight, I actually went out
with Chip in high school.
오늘밤 진짜 고교시절의
칩 매튜스를 만났어
Honey, I'm sorry.
이를 어째
괜찮아, 칩 매튜스를
사정없이 차버렸으니까
Not only did I get
to go out with Chip...
...I got to dump Chip.
-That's so great!
-I know.
- 멋지다!
- 그렇지?
보험회사에선 뭐래?
What did the insurance company say?
보험 가입 안 했으면
전화하지 말라더라
They said, "You don't have insurance.
Stop calling us."
You didn't tell her?
얘기 안 했어?
Okay, fine.
그래, 좋아
피비?
- 왔어?
- 그래
Listen...
저기... 이 고양이의
주인은 어린 소녀야
...this cat belongs to a little girl.
거리에 전단이 깔렸어
There are flyers all over the place.
미안해
I'm sorry, sweetie.
원한다면 우리가 돌려줄게
We can take her
back with you if you want.
But, you know, she chose to find me.
하지만 엄마는 날 택했어
그 결정을 존중해야지
I have to respect her decision, right?
-That's a good call.
-That's right.
- 그럴 듯하네
- 맞는 말이야
뭐야, 제발 그만둬
Enough is enough.
I'm sorry you feel guilty about
spending time with your new mom.
생모와 시간을 보내는 게
약간은 죄책감이 들겠지만
이건 엄마가 아니라
고양이야
But this isn't your old mom.
This is a cat.
고양이 훌리오라고
Julio the cat.
Not Mom! Cat.
엄마가 아니라 고양이!
Ross, how many parents have you lost?
넌 부모님 돌아가신 적 있니?
None.
없는데
그럼 세상을 뜬 부모님이
돌아온 기분을 모르겠구나
Then you don't know how it feels
when one of them comes back.
난 우리 엄마라고 믿어
I believe this is my mother.
Even if I'm wrong, who cares?
내가 틀렸다 해도
무슨 상관이야?
Just be a friend, okay?
Be supportive.
친구라면 내 맘을 이해해 줘
I'm sorry.
미안하다
Okay.
그래
I don't know what to say.
할말이 없다
You could say...
어머니께 사과 안 드려?
...you're sorry to her mom.
좋게 받아주실 거야
I think she would like that.
Come here. Here, come here.
자, 이리 온
Mrs. Buffay?
부페이 부인?
정말 죄송합니다
Sorry about what I said.
제가 고양이라고 한 건
정말 무례한 언사였어요
It was insensitive of me to say...
...that you were just a cat...
...when, clearly, you are also...
제 친구 엄마의
환생이라는 걸 몰랐네요
...the reincarnated spirit...
...of my friend's mother.
Thank you.
고마워
We both forgive you.
용서할게
그 소녀는 어떡하지?
What will you do about
the little girl?
그래, 잘 들으세요
Listen.
Mom, I hope you know
you still mean a lot to me.
엄만 제게 중요한 분이세요
언제든 돌아오셔도 좋아요
You're welcome
to come back anytime.
피비, 소파로 환생해서
돌아오시면 참 고마울 텐데
If she'd come back as a couch,
we'd really appreciate it.
Come on.
I'll take you home.
제가 데려다 드릴게요
- 같이 가자
- 나도
-I'll go with you.
-Me too.
I got an extra futon.
남는 이불이 있는데
Dude, you don't have to brag.
We got nothing here.
지금 유세하냐?
여기 뭐가 있다고
도로시 코프먼을 추모하며
You know....
이거 아냐?
여기 참 한적하다
It's peaceful out here.